Ashish Khatiwada

Software Engineer

ashishkhatiwada091@gmail.com

+977 9860103347

Kathmandu, Nepal



linkedin.com/in/ashish-khatiwada-18415020a



github.com/bot-alert

A professional software engineer who understands how to use new tools and technological advancements to drive improvements throughout the software development lifecycle. Extensive industrial and full life cycle experience in a java-based environment, as well as outstanding analytical, design, and problem-solving skills. Excellent communication abilities, as well as the ability to create and fine-tune new features.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Code Fusion Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

10/2021 - Present

Kathmandu. Nepal

Code Fusion Technologies is specialized in different growing fields of Nepal such as e-governance, education, and management systems.

- Build and integrated Bulk-SMS microservice API to the existing HMIS system.
- Create an Android application for tuberculosis care that includes automated data sync in the presence of an internet connection and a QR-based ID scan.
- I upgraded the HMIS (Health Management Information System) entirely under the guideline of the Ministry of Health and Population 2078.
- Worked on Spring Framework-based applications such as ICMS, PMIS, PIS, SAMYANTRA, and many more.
- Worked integrating DHIS-2 API with HMIS reporting application.
- I upgrade the java of HMIS form java 8 to java 17 along with spring framework upgrade

Ethical Hacking Tutor

Insight Academy

03/2017 - 03/2018 Insight Academy is entrance preparation institutes. Kathmandu, Nepal

Achievements/Tasks

- Taught fundamentals of ethical hacking for SEE passed students (2-month session for the year 2017 and 2018)

Computer Teacher

Peace Point Boarding School

02/2017 - 06/2017

Kathmandu, Nepal

Achievements/Tasks

I taught computer science from fourth to eighth grade.

EDUCATION

BSc. CSIT (Bachelors of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology)

Tribhuvan University

02/2017 - 03/2022

Kathmandu, Nepal

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Digital-Canteen (09/2020 - 02/2021)

- github.com/bot-alert/Digital-Canteen
- Digital-Canteen is designed to reduce crowding around the counter and make the meal ordering procedure easier.
- Implemented live token numbering system.
- It consists of an admin analytics system, QR creation, and orders scanning.

Digital Pahichan (01/2021 - 05/2021)

- Digital Pahichan is a means of making digital government more accessible and straightforward by placing all of the residents' information in a single app.
- github.com/bot-alert/Digital-Pahichan
- Can be used to send current location coordinates to police in case of

Fileshare (02/2021 - 03/2021)

- github.com/bot-alert/Fileshare
- A file sharing web app is a program designed to allow for the safe transfer of data.

CERTIFICATES

Building Scalable Java Microservices with Spring Boot and Spring Cloud 🗹

Google

CS50's Introduction to Computer Science Harvard University

Redis for Java Developers 🗗

Redis university

CyberSecurity Essentials

MongoDB for Java Developers 🗗

MongoDB University

Java Programming 🗹

Great Learnina

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

JavaScript

Limited Working Proficiency

Shell Scripting

Professional Working Proficiency